He should be here somewhere.
That means he has landed on our side.
Any update on the rescue chopper?
Jai Hind.
The Indian Army
has spotted Ahuja's parachute.
Where, sir?
He's drifted across the LoC.
Ahuja is in PoK, Tony.
Dhali!
Ahuja ejected, man! Hurry up!
This Ahuja…
Always going overboard.
No problem.
Let's bring him back.
Sinha!
Ahuja has ejected.
We have to go look for him.
What? When?
Just a little while ago.
We don't have much time.
Is there a chopper ready?
-Is Nubra One ready at the takeoff point?
-Yes, sir.
Run the final checks quickly.
I want to take off in two minutes.
Did Ahuja activate his rescue beacon?
Ahuja isn't in friendly territory, Sinha.
I know him well.
He will neither use the beacon
nor let them use it.
Where the hell do you think you're going?
We are going to get Ahuja, sir.
Ahuja is in Pakistan, Tony.
That doesn't matter, sir.
Our choppers are fitted
with both guns and rockets.
We will rescue him, sir.
You have to trust us.
What if they shoot you?
Who's going to go look for you?
It's a trap. Basic military strategy.
Sir, we can't just sit back
and do nothing.
It is a diplomatic matter now.
I'll talk to the government,
take it to the highest level.
You cannot cross the LoC.
Understood?
In breaking news coming from South Asia,
the Indian Air Force has confirmed
that two of its fighter pilots
are missing in action
after their jets were reportedly shot down
over the Line of Control
in Kashmir's Kargil sector.
World leaders are monitoring
the developments closely
amidst widespread concern
that this may prove to be
a dangerous tipping point
in the ongoing Kargil conflict
between the two…
Long live Pakistan, sir.
I'm watching the news, Aziz.
-Well done.
-Thank you, sir.
But now this issue
will escalate internationally, Aziz.
American satellites
will be monitoring the Line of Control.
So, for now,
halt all movement of soldiers
and their supplies.
Sir, India has deployed
15,000 more soldiers in the Kargil sector.
Stopping the movement now--
Whether it's 1,000 or 15,000,
what difference does it make, Aziz?
It's been over three weeks
since we were discovered.
We have killed 250 of their soldiers,
shot down two jets.
Has the Indian Air Force or the Army
managed to hurt us in any way?
As long as we hold the height advantage,
we'll keep crushing
both their Army and their Air Force.
Right, sir.
I trust both pilots are in our custody?
We've caught one, sir.
He's unconscious at the moment.
And the second?
The search is ongoing, sir.
The area has been identified.
We'll get him soon.
Excellent.
Let's see how many more pilots
the Indian Air Force
is willing to send to their deaths.
We've found the parachute, sir.
The Station Commander himself is here.
I hope it's nothing serious?
No. He's not in ceremonial uniform.
Ajay had to eject during a mission.
We are waiting for further information.
As soon as we find out more,
we'll update you.
General Zinni, what a pleasant surprise.
Is it, Mr. Prime Minister?
My office has requested meetings
five times in the last week.
I apologize, General.
The situation at the LoC is quite tense.
Which is precisely why I'm calling.
President Clinton is deeply concerned
and wants you to de-escalate immediately.
They're not our troops, General.
They are Mujahideen.
Delhi claims that it's your army
disguised as militants.
Quite frankly,
given the scale, it is compelling.
Who do you trust, General?
Your old ally, Pakistan,
who stood by you faithfully
for the last 50 years--
Speaking of allies, Mr. Prime Minister,
what is your army chief doing in Beijing?
That's a personal visit, General.
It has nothing to do with this situation.
Mr. Sharif, you do understand
that if India and Pakistan
go to nuclear war,
100 million people could lose their lives
in the immediate aftermath?
Right now, sir,
you are just one reckless decision away
from setting it off.
President Clinton
is counting on your leadership,
Mr. Prime Minister.
This is my third war.
And today…
may well be the most difficult day…
of my entire career.
With great regret,
I am suspending Operation Safed Sagar.
With due respect, sir,
we were first ordered
not to cross the LoC
while engaging the enemy.
We didn't cross it.
Then we were told
not to cross the LoC even to rescue Ahuja.
We didn't cross it then either.
But now we're being told not to fight
even from our side of the LoC?
How can this be, sir?
Tony, we have to face the hard facts.
In the last two days,
we have lost two aircraft and two pilots.
We can't go down without a fight, sir.
Sir, I agree with Tony.
We have to keep fighting.
You're all missing the big picture here.
This is the Western Air Command's
area of responsibility.
From Rajasthan to Jammu and Kashmir.
The area spans 3.5 lakh square kilometers.
On this map,
Kargil is just a tiny dot.
If losses continue at this rate,
then within a month,
in an attempt to protect this tiny dot,
the entire Western Air Command
will be engaged.
And if the enemy opens another front,
how will we protect
the rest of these borders?
Tony, I'm angry, too.
But we work on cold strategy.
We will strike,
but from outside missile range.
But, sir,
that's 10,000 feet above the target.
If we can't achieve precision
even from this close,
how will we from that height?
That's exactly why we are going to wait.
The target is at 18,000 feet.
Bombing needs to be done from 30,000 feet.
And only an advanced aircraft
like the Mirage can do this.
Because only the Mirage 2000 has
laser-guided bombing capability,
which can lock onto targets from far away
from the peak,
beyond missile range.
And it can strike before
the enemy can react
and safely return.
But unfortunately,
they're not ready yet either,
because they don't have
laser-guided bombs.
The Americans have once again rejected
our request for laser-guided bombs.
It's clear America is playing with us.
We have the capabilities,
but not the equipment.
So we'll make our own laser-guided bombs,
and showcase the innovative capabilities
of the Indian Air Force to the world.
We have old bombs from 1971.
We'll fit these Paveway laser kits to them
and lead this Mirage 2000 into believing
that they're laser-guided bombs.
Until the jet accepts this hack,
nobody goes home.
At any cost…
we need to fool this jet.
Sangy sir,
there's a call for you from Srinagar.
Hello?
Sangy,
it's Baldy.
Baldy?
How are you?
Any news of Ahuja sir?
There's no news.
Our operations have also been halted.
Yes, Chhabra sir told me.
Tell me something.
What's happening with the Mirages?
When do you think you'll be operational?
We are trying our best.
Everyone's working around the clock.
Listen, Baldy,
how's Dhali?
He was with Ahuja sir, wasn't he?
Ever since he came back,
he's barely spoken to anyone.
Maybe he is blaming himself.
We're all just hoping
that wherever Ahuja sir is,
he comes back safe.
Nothing should happen
to either of our pilots.
Jaswant ji, please send
a message to Islamabad.
They should be treated properly.
Otherwise,
the outcome will be grave for Pakistan.
Yes.
Get him down.
Get down.
Well done, Ajmal.
You know what you have to do.
Yes, sir.
Move.
Squadron Leader Ajay Ahuja,
what were you doing so close to the LoC?
What was your objective?
Under the Geneva Conventions of 1949,
prisoners of war
are not mandated to answer questions
posed by the enemy.
Speak up!
Answer the question directly.
Why are you here?
Perhaps, you should first ask yourself…
You…
Why did you come inside my country?
With India maintaining
that both jets were shot down
on their side of the Line of Control,
the fog of war in Kargil has now thickened
into a global diplomatic crisis.
Speaking earlier today,
the US Secretary of State
urged maximum restraint,
reminding the world that a nuclear
exchange between India and Pakistan
-could result in a hundred million deaths…
-Aziz.
-…in the immediate aftermath.
-Is the other pilot in our custody?
Yes, sir. He's been taken to Skardu.
And has he agreed to accept the truth?
Sorry, sir, I don't understand.
That he was ordered
to cross the Line of Control
and bomb our forward bases.
It's very important to get
this on-camera statement from him, Aziz.
So that we can mislead the world
into thinking that
the real aggressor is India, not us.
I'll check, sir.
But General Hassan tells me
the officer is extremely stubborn.
General Hassan isn't capable
of handling every situation.
You see to it yourself.
Copy that, sir. Understood.
I'll leave for Skardu immediately.
I am asking once again.
Which base were you ordered
to bomb inside Pakistan?
I am telling you again.
There were no bombs in my aircraft.
And I also didn't…
intend to enter Pakistan.
Lies!
Absolute lies.
Which base?
Major Ajmal!
-Which base?
-Major Ajmal!
What's going on here?
Untie the rope.
Put his uniform back on.
And you.
Fetch Dr. Bukhari.
What are you doing, Hassan?
This is Skardu, sir.
This is how we extract information here.
Hassan, this is different.
Do you have any idea
how important his statement is?
I apologize for Major Ajmal's conduct.
But you are very stubborn.
And our soldiers…
respond to stubbornness
in this fashion.
Now, what can one do?
You can, General Khan.
You can give them good training.
So that they know
that any form of torture
meted out to a prisoner of war
is a violation of the Geneva Conventions.
What Geneva Conventions?
They apply only when
the armies of two nations
are at war with each other.
Those people who have entered Kargil,
in response to which
you have entered our territory,
are Mujahideen.
I'm sorry, General Khan, I didn't know
that by merely wearing a Pathani suit,
Pakistan's army becomes Mujahideen.
Aren't you worried about Ankur and Alka?
Sir, you don't need to worry about them.
They are in the safest place in India.
And you're here,
in Pakistan's most secure army base.
No one will come here to save you.
Here, only…
I can help you.
For that,
you have to help me first.
Please have some tea.
General Musharraf,
Beijing welcomes you
during difficult times.
-Thank you.
-Please, sit.
My deepest sympathies
regarding your embassy in Belgrade.
Three journalists dead.
"American mistake," they claim.
We have a saying in Urdu.
"Their own roof is falling apart,
but they are off
to repair others' houses."
And this is what America is doing.
For the last few weeks,
India has been displaying unrestrained
aggression along the Line of Control.
And yet,
my prime minister is receiving
daily calls from Clinton.
What should we do?
Should we sit back and allow India
to take over our country?
America is acting through India. Trust me.
We can easily take on India.
But America?
General,
we also have a saying in Mandarin.
"A frog at the bottom of the well
cannot fathom the depth of the ocean."
It is a very stupid thing,
what you've done in Kargil, General.
Sparking war in the midst
of a historic peace process,
while both sides have nuclear weapons.
You're playing with fire.
China has always
supported Pakistan in the past.
But this time,
you're on your own.
Your safety has sparked concern
not just in India,
but across the world as well.
So,
we will record a video of you.
We got this written in Hindustani for you.
All you have to do
is look into the camera,
and read whatever
is written on it properly.
So, let's get started?
Zubair.
"I, Squadron Leader Ajay Ahuja,
am making this statement
of my own free will and in my senses."
"Today, on May 27, 1999,
when I…"
WHEN I WAS ATTEMPTING AN ATTACK
ON A PAKISTANI MILITARY BASE
While I was engaged in a non-offensive
mission within Indian territory,
then the Pakistani Army
that has infiltrated Kargil…
-What happened, sir?
-Don't they teach you to read over there?
They do, sir.
How to read and how to fight, too.
But with principles.
What do they teach you
this side of the border, sir?
So, according to you,
your mission was limited
to Indian airspace only.
Then would you care to explain
what you're doing
at a Pakistan Army base right now?
Sir, the Pakistan Army
hidden in our mountains
fired a Stinger missile at my jet.
I ejected…
in India.
My parachute carried me into Pakistan.
So,
entering Pakistan…
was never your intention?
Affirmative, sir.
Very well. Let's talk straight.
Tell one lie for us.
Then, inshallah,
go back and collect
your medal for bravery.
Which country awards medals for lying?
And anyway, no medal is valuable enough…
for me to betray my country.
You also have another option.
We will shift you to London.
You'll get so much…
that you won't need a medal…
or your uniform.
There's something special, sir,
about this uniform.
It's not like any passerby
can buy it off the street and wear it.
To wear it,
you have to pledge your life to India.
Anyway,
I have told you everything
I'm supposed to tell you.
You're a three-star general.
Your time is very valuable.
Don't waste it on me.
Jai Hind, sir.
He who cannot understand the difference
between principles and madness…
neither I…
nor God can save him.
Aziz, what's the update?
Sir, I tried everything,
but he's very stubborn, sir.
If he is stubborn,
then make an example of him.
Do you know what I mean?
Sir, but the international community?
Screw the international community.
Make such an example of him that before
they even think of entering Pakistan,
their blood runs cold.
Sir.
Jai Hind.
"Compound fracture of the leg tibia.
Multiple gunshot wounds
to the thoracic cavity and cranium.
Extensive…
cigarette-induced burn injuries across
the abdominal region and genitalia."
Signs of deliberate mutilation,
including broken fingers--"
Everything is visible, Doctor.
I can see it.
All that they've done to him.
Can we take the body?
Yes, sir.
But there is a problem.
What's the problem?
The coffin Pakistan sent his body in
is a foot and a half too short.
And inside that only, they have…
So, all this?
-Who'll arrange all of this?
-I'll arrange it, sir.
The situation in the Kargil War
is becoming increasingly grave.
Today, even a joint operation
of the Indian Army and Air Force
failed to recapture the Tololing Complex.
In this effort, both forces
have suffered heavy setbacks.
The intruders,
using surface-to-air missiles,
targeted Mi-17 attack helicopters
of the Indian Air Force.
In just two days,
this is the third Air Force aircraft
that has been shot down.
In this incident,
Squadron Leader Rajiv Pundir,
Flight Lieutenant Subramaniam Muhilan,
Sergeant PVNR Prasad,
and Sergeant Raj Kishore Sahu
have attained martyrdom.
Earlier, after shooting down
Squadron Leader Ajay Ahuja's MiG-21,
the Pakistani Army
had subjected him to brutal torture.
WAKE UP, PAKISTAN,
OR BECOME A GRAVEYARD!
There is widespread outrage across India,
even as Pakistan claims
that Squadron Leader Ajay Ahuja died
from injuries sustained during ejection.
Squadron Leader Ahuja
unfortunately had been killed
in the accident.
India has formally accused Pakistan
of violating the Geneva Conventions.
The killing of a downed pilot,
if confirmed,
would constitute a grave breach
of international law.
This is a cold-blooded murder,
an act of cowardice,
on the part of Pakistani regulars.
General Aziz, why didn't you tell us
that the Indian fighter pilot
was tortured to death?
Sir, our official stance
is absolutely clear.
Squadron Leader Ajay Ahuja
died due to the ejection impact.
India is blaming us,
saying we are violating
the Geneva Conventions.
America is checking in with me daily,
pressurizing us
to release the other pilot immediately.
Aziz sahib,
immediately start the process
of handing over that pilot to India.
Long live Pakistan.
General Musharraf?
Did you come straight from the airport?
I thought I shouldn't delay too much
in delivering the good news, Sharif sahib.
China has congratulated us
on giving India a bloody nose.
China is with us, Mian sahib.
And if America
still pressures us to withdraw,
we can count on China.
That's wonderful news.
Meaning, we don't need America anymore?
That's right.
Sartaj sahib,
you and Nawaz sahib
keep the Americans occupied.
It's time…
we deal with Delhi directly.
You were the one I trusted,
Tony.
Why did you let him go there?
Why?
Fire!
BHISIANA CREMATORIUM
Sir, before the war of '71,
there was an explosion
caused by someone else's safety lapse.
My father had shrapnel lodged in his body.
Even surgery could not remove them.
After a few years, he left us.
And today, we lost Ahuja sir.
He was like a father to me, sir.
I'm really very sorry, Sangy.
I have to fly in this war, sir.
I have to fly.
I have to go back to Golden Arrows.
To my family.
They killed him, Kamal.
They tortured him.
The bastards shot him point-blank.
And they're saying that
he died from ejection impact.
They're lying, and here we are
sitting with our operation on hold.
Tony, it's not your fault.
I called him here.
I called him here!
This was not his regular posting.
"Ahuja, come." He came, and…
Hello?
Sir, Wing Commander Sandeep Chhabra
is on the line from Gwalior.
Connect.
Sandy.
I'm very sorry, Tony.
I know Ahuja was special.
Sorry won't do, Sandy.
We have to bomb them to Dark Ages.
We're boiling inside, too, Tony.
But we can't fly the Mirages
until trials are done.
Won't get clearance.
How much longer
are your trials going to take?
I don't know, man.
French plane, Israeli laser kit,
old Indian bombs from 1971.
Hacking all this together
and making it work is a tricky setup.
But we are trying.
We're trying, Tony.
Well, listen,
Sangy wants to come back to you.
He is emotional.
But I'm okay with it.
What's he going to do
even if he comes here?
The entire operation
has been suspended here.
How strange, isn't it, Sandy?
You can bomb outside missile range,
but you don't have bombs.
The MiG-27 has bombs,
but they cannot bomb
from outside missile range.
We have GPS,
we can get close to the target,
but bombing…
Tony? Hello?
Are you there?
Sandy, I'll… I'll call you back.
I'll call you back.
We…
don't need to halt the operation.
Meaning?
Kamal, we…
We can bomb, but…
But?
But what?
I will not get permission.
Permission?
Did they ask for permission
before entering our country?
before torturing Ahuja?
Sardar,
do whatever you want to do,
however you want to do it.
Just do it.
They think sitting up there at that
altitude, they can do what they want.
They are wrong.
We will mourn no more.
We won't take any more photos either.
Our jets
have cameras installed in place of bombs.
But the place is for bombs, isn't it?
Now, we will bomb.
We have GPS.
We can fly above the clouds
to reach our target.
And staying outside their missile range,
we can rain fire on them.
It's never been done before.
But we'll do it.
-Are you with me?
-Yes, sir!
Tony, when was the last time
a photo-recce squadron
took on the role of a bombing squadron?
That too in the middle of a war.
Sir, when was the last time
any air force in the world
fought a war at 18,000 feet?
My objection is purely technical.
MiGs are designed
to drop bombs from 20,000 feet.
Not from 30,000 feet.
Sir, the machine is ready
and so is the squadron.
And you yourself said that
we need to bomb them
from outside their missile range,
just like the Mirages.
So we're outside their missile range.
Fair enough.
The army will give you
the coordinates of the peaks.
But how will you calculate
your bomb release point?
Sir, we will conduct our own trials
and create our own charts.
All right.
I will officially
give you clearance
for high-altitude GPS bombing.
But…
the error rate of your trials
should be within 200 meters.
Sir.
The Army is struggling.
They're losing men every day.
That's why I had
to commit Air Force support,
even while knowing
that the chances of this unconventional
strategy being successful…
is only five percent.
Like every time before,
we don't have another option, sir.
Now either we will create history,
or get buried in it.
Subtitle translation by: Smriti Shalini